Once our clustering algorithm has identified clusters and prototype trajectories,
クラスタリングアルゴリズムが クラスターとプロトタイプトラジェクトリー
in this case three clusters with three prototype trajectories each,
この場合それぞれ 3 つのプロトタイプトラジェクトリーを持つ 3 つのクラスターを特定すると
we can begin the job of online prediction for a vehicle that we meet on the road.
道路上で出会う車両の動きをオンラインで予測できます
First, we observed the vehicle's partial trajectory.
まず 車両の部分的トラジェクトリーを観察します
Next we compare it to
次に これを各クラスターのプロトタイプトラジェクトリーの
the corresponding segments of the prototype trajectories for each cluster.
対応するセグメントと比較します
This comparison is done using
この比較は 前にクラスタリングの実行に使用したものと同じ
the same similarity measure we used earlier to perform the clustering.
類似性の測定を使用して行います
The belief for each cluster is updated based on
各クラスターの信念は 部分的トラジェクトリーがプロトタイプトラジェクトリーに
how similar the partial trajectory is to the prototype trajectories.
どれくらい類似しているかに基づいて更新されます
And finally, we compute a predicted trajectory for each cluster.
そして最後に 各クラスターの予測されたトラジェクトリーを計算します
For example, by taking the most similar prototype trajectory.
たとえば 最も類似したプロトタイプトラジェクトリーを使うことによって行います
Let's make this more clear by following this car forward
時間 T = 0 から T = 1 までこの車を
in time from T equals zero to T equals one.
前方に追って これを明確にしましょう
Let's go through these steps.
これらをステップごとに見ていきましょう
One, we observe the partial trajectory between time zero and one.
1 時間 0 と 1 の間に部分的トラジェクトリーを観察します
It is this green line behind the vehicle.
これは車両後ろの緑色の線です
Two, well since all of the prototype trajectories overlap up to this point,
2 プロトタイプトラジェクトリーのすべてがこの点まではオーバーラップするため
the trajectory comparison step will yield the same probability for each cluster.
トラジェクトリー比較ステップは各クラスターに対して同じ確率となります
Three, even though there is no clear winner within each cluster we still have to choose
3 各クラスター内に明らかな勝者はありませんが
one prototype trajectory to represent each cluster and we
各クラスターを代表するために 1 つのプロトタイプトラジェクトリーを選択する必要があり
broadcast these three trajectories with their associated probabilities.
これら 3 つのトラジェクトリーを関連する確率とともにブロードキャストします
Next, a T equal two- things get more interesting.
次に T = 2 でもっと面白くなります
First, let's get rid of the car so we can see the trajectory more clearly.
まず トラジェクトリーを見やすくするために車を消しましょう
Now when you make a comparison of
ここで 部分的トラジェクトリーと 9 つのプロトタイプトラジェクトリー
the partial trajectory with the nine prototype trajectories,
を比較すると 車両の部分的トラジェクトリーが
we find that the vehicle's partial trajectory
紫色や青色よりも赤色に
seems more similar to the red than purple or blue.
似ていることがわかります
When we update the associated probabilities we might get something like this.
これらの関連確率を更新すると このようなものが得られます
Note that red grows in probability and the blue and purple both shrink,
赤色の確率が高くなり 青色と紫色両方が低くなりますが 青色は紫色よりも
but blue shrinks more than purple since the partial trajectory is a worse match for blue.
さらに低くなります これは部分的トラジェクトリーが青色に対してマッチが劣っているからです
Then, we pick the best prototype trajectory for
続いて 各クラスターに対する最良のプロトタイプトラジェクトリーを選択し
each cluster and use them to represent the future trajectory of the car.
それらを使用して車の将来のトラジェクトリーを表します
As we continue this process,
このプロセスを続けていくと
we see the probability for the red cluster quickly approaches one.
赤色のクラスターの確率がすぐに 1 に近づくことがわかります